Arun Krishna K

Frontend Developer

Contact: arunkrishna.kannan@gmail.com |+919655390027 Location: 49, Vallalar Nagar, Koothapakkam, Cuddalore – 607002 <u>GitHub Profile</u> / <u>LinkedIn Profile</u>

Skills

Programming Languages: C, Python

Frontend Development: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, ReactJS, JavaScript, jQuery, Django

Backend Development: MySQL, MongoDB

Version Control: GitHub, GIT

Networking Tools: Wireshark, CISCO Packet Tracer

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Mint)

Summary

Experienced Frontend with a background in IT and 2+ years of experience growing revenue for a Cloud lion IT firm. Seeking to leverage Senior developer expertise. Good Communication and technically have a knowledge in core computer and computer Networks

Work Experience

Cloud lion, Canada (Remote) Jan 2022 - Present Junior Developer

- Worked in the Zoho Application like Zoho creator, CRM to customize the product for the users with the help of deluge script
- · Created the Widget Applications using the HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React JS for the front-end development

Excellence Telecom Sept 2018 - Aug 2021 Quality Analyst

- Worked on Quality Checking for the Mobile Phones and software troubleshooting capabilities
- · Verified the each and every cases of the Phone working principles and added the report of issues.

Project Work

Visavie: I recently developed the user interface (UI) for a module designed for a residence for elderly people in Canada. This involved creating an intuitive and accessible layout to meet the needs of the elderly residents. The design focuses on ease of use, ensuring that residents can navigate the interface without difficulty.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Zoho CRM (Deluge)

AIM Insurance: I have created an enrolment form for an insurance client. The form is built using HTML, CSS, and jQuery, ensuring a user-friendly and responsive design. This form allows clients to easily submit their information for insurance coverage.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Zoho Creator (Deluge)

REC-Protect: I have created the form and backend flow for an application using Zoho Creator. This development utilized Deluge script to ensure seamless integration and functionality. The form captures user inputs efficiently, while the backend flow processes and manages the data effectively.

Tech Stack: Zoho Creator (Deluge)

Mark Edward: I have developed the backend functionality for this website using Zoho Creator and Deluge script. This involved writing custom scripts to handle data processing, automation, and business logic. The implementation ensures that the backend operations run smoothly, providing a good foundation for the website's features and services.

Tech Stack: Zoho Creator, Zoho CRM (Deluge)

Pal Plus: I have developed a hotel booking web application featuring a calendar-based widget using jQuery and various other components. This widget allows users to select dates seamlessly for their bookings.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Zoho Creator (Deluge)

Education

St. Peters University Aug 2014 - May 2018 B.Tech. in Information Technology *CGPA: 6.58/10* Relevant Coursework: Object Oriented Programming, Databases, Discrete Maths, Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Advance Data Structures and Algorithms.

Courses and Certificates

- Python for Everybody: In the Coursera I done a certification in Python it covers the fundamentals of python Certificate
- **Aruba Networks:** Completed the Aruba networks for the basic of computer networking it covers the IP address, OSI model, DHCP, TCP and UDP concepts

Certificate

• Google Support IT fundamentals: Completed the IT support fundamentals in the Coursera in this one learned the basic troubleshooting and OS

Certificate

- CCNA Master Class: I have completed the CCNA preparation given by instructors David Bombal and kevin wallace this course briefly describes the network model TCP/IP, Spanning Tree protocol, IPV4 address and IPV6, network security fundamentals, Wireless modules, IP routing, packet tracer labs

 Certificate
- Shiaas Foundation: Completed the Python basic and learned the framework of Django and created the personal portfolio based on Django
- Linux Unatched Course: Completed the fundamentals of Linux provided by CISCO, it covers the CLI commands in Linux and operating the terminal and introduction to Bash Scripting

Personal Project Work

• Recipe App (2024): Crafted with ReactJS, our recipe application brings the art of cooking to life with seamless user experience and dynamic, interactive features with API.

Food-Recipe

• Weather App (2024): Worked in ReactJS, our weather application provides real-time forecasts with intuitive design, with the API.

Search-Weather

- Designed LOLK UI (2022): Designed the UI for the Application for freelance it is non-profit organization which helps the poor children around the world and it is medical related treatments are provided with free of cost
- Ezhuthathigaram: Designed the UI for the Application, this based on the archaeological site which we can find the which inscription that geographical location and time period it is a collective of all the inscription in Tamil Nadu
- Internet Speed Test: Designed the web application for the Internet speed test using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and hosted it on GitHub

Internet Speed Test

Languages

- Tamil Read, Write, Speak
- English Read, Write, Speak